ipostparcels.com 2019-11-27

# Privacy Policy

##  **ipostparcels Privacy Notice - DHL Parcel UK**

This statement was last updated on 27.02.2019.

DHL Parcel UK (hereinafter called 'DHL') is pleased that you have visited our website and are interested in our company, products and services. It is important to us to protect your personal data during handling throughout the entire business process.

Please be aware that the national legal requirements for data protection and the handling of personal data may vary from country to country. Therefore, if you visit the relevant DHL country websites you will learn more about country specific information on data protection.

In the following, we explain what information DHL collects when you visit our website and how this information is processed and for what specific purposes.

##  **General Information**

###  **What is personal data?**

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

This means personal data has to be information that relates to an individual. That individual must be identified or identifiable either directly from one or more identifiers or from factors specific to the individual.

This includes information such as your real name, address, telephone number and date of birth. Information which cannot be linked to your real identity - such as favourite websites or number of users of a site - is not considered personal data.

###  **Who is responsible?**

This Privacy Notice applies for the data processing carried out by: Deutsche Post AG

If you have any queries with regard to the processing of your personal data, please contact the Data Protection Officer. The Data Protection Team is also available to help with data subject access requests, take suggestions or handle complaints.

Data Protection Officer for DHL

Gabriela Krader, LL.M

Deutsche Post AG

Corporate Centre - 524

53250 Bonn

**Data protection officer’s contact details:**

For enquiries relating specifically to DHL Parcel UK, please contact the Data Protection Team at:

Telephone: 02477 711 203 (ext. 5203) 

Written requests should be sent to:

Data Protection Officer

DHL Parcel UK

Hillman Way

Ryton-on-Dunsmore

CV8 3ED

###  **Purposes of data processing - essential information**

We process your data in order, for instance, to

  * perform the contract concluded with you or a sender;
  * make visits to our websites/apps as pleasant as possible;
  * send you the newsletter if you subscribe to it;
  * send or display to you - where permitted - targeted advertising;
  * carry out a credit check, where necessary;
  * handle your requests via our customer service department;
  * fulfil obligations as part of statutory requirements;
  * fulfil our security requirements (e.g., for crime detection purposes);
  * compile statistics; and
  * for purposes of quality assurance, process optimisation and planning certainty.

You can find further details below under the relevant headings, including the type of data, the purpose of processing and the legal basis,

###  **What are my data subject's rights?**

You have the following rights:

  * You have the right to be informed about the collection and use of your personal data;
  * You have the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified, or completed if it is incomplete;
  * You have the right to have person data erased. This right is not absolute and only applies in certain circumstances, as it must be permitted by law and in compliance with existing contractual conditions;
  * You have the right to request access to your personal data; and
  * You have the right to request the restriction or suppression of your personal data although this is not an absolute right and will only apply in certain circumstances.
  * You may lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. Find here the competent data protection authority.

**Right to object**

Article 21 of the GDPR gives individuals the right to object to the processing of their personal data. The right to object only applies in certain circumstances. Whether it applies will depend on the purposes for processing and the lawful basis for processing.

To exercise your rights, simply get in touch with us by using the [contact form](https://www.dhlparcel.co.uk/en/toolbar/footer/privacy-notice/form-data-protection.html).

###  **Storageperiod**

Personal data is stored **for no longer than is necessary for the purposes of which the personal data is processed** ;

Where statutory periods do not exist, the data will be stored for contract performance and invoicing purposes and as proof of the correct performance of the contract, until the liability periods expire, and it will subsequently be erased.

###  **What is the DPDHL Data Privacy Policy?**

The DPDHL Data Privacy Policy regulates the Group-wide standards for data processing. If you are interested in learning more about the DPDHL Data Privacy Policy, please use the following link:

##  **Visiting our Website**

###  **Visiting our Website**

DHL is committed to preserving the privacy of the users of our websites. When you visit our web pages, our web servers always temporarily save the connection data of the computer connecting to our site, a list of the web pages that you visit within our site, the date and duration of your visit, the IP address of your device, the identification data of the type of browser and operation system used as well as the website through which you linked to our site. Additional personal information such as your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address is not collected unless you provide this data voluntarily, e.g. while completing an online contact form, as part of a registration, survey, competition, fulfilment of contract or an information request. This data is only collected and processed based on the original purpose of collection.

The legal basis for the processing of the aforementioned data categories is Art. 6 (1) f of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)).

As far as you have enabled geo localisation functions in your browser, respectively in your operating system we will use this data to offer you location-based services (e. g. location of the nearest branch, packing station etc.). We will not use this data for any other purpose. If you disable this function your data will be immediately deleted.

###  **Performance of a contract**

For contractual reasons, we also need personal data to provide our services and comply with the obligations arising from contractual agreements concluded with you. This data is used e. g. for performing a (shipment) contract, managing customer data, handling payments and, as the case may be, assessing credit worthiness. Certain shipment data will also be provided to the authorities of the country of transit or destination for customs and tax clearance or for security screening, as required by the laws of such country. The information provided would usually include: shipper name and address, receiver name and address, description of the goods, number of pieces, weight and value of shipment.

The legal basis is necessary for the performance of a contract (Art. 6 (1) b) GDPR).

Further information on data protection in specific services and products is available in the section Products and Services.

###  **Processing for advertising purposes**

If you are an existing customer of DHL your postal data (e.g. name, address) will be processed to contact you in order to provide you with the latest information about our offers, news, products and services. Apart from an existing consent, we will process your e-mail address exclusively in order to provide you with information regarding DHL's own and similar products.

Legal basis for the aforementioned processing is Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR. The processing of customer data for own direct marketing purposes is regarded as carried out for a legitimate interest.

You have right to object at any time to this processing. To exercise your right, simply get in touch with us by using the contact details mentioned above under Who is responsible?.

If you register for one of our newsletters, we are entitled to use your e-mail address for this purpose. You may unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by clicking the relevant link at the bottom of the newsletter.

In case you file an objection or unsubscribe from our newsletter services the respective data will be deleted and no longer be processed for such purposes.

###  **Will my data be passed on to third parties?**

To enhance and improve our customer experiences, we may share your contact details with third parties to enable you to provide feedback on the service you have received from DHL Parcel UK. Some personal data may be shared with non-marketing third parties, this is necessary to help process orders and provide customer based services. For instance, it may be necessary to pass on your address and order data to our contractors when you order products. Further information on data protection in specific services and products is available below in section Products and Services.

External service providers that process data on our behalf are contractually obliged to maintain strict confidentiality as per Art. 28 GDPR. DHL retains responsibility for safeguarding your information in such circumstances. The service providers follow the instructions of DHL and this is guaranteed by technical and organisational measures, as well as by means of checks and controls.

###  **Online presence and website optimization**

We use tracking software to determine how many users visit our website and how often. We do not use this software to collect individual personal data or individual IP addresses. The data is used solely in an anonymous and summarised form for statistical purposes and for developing the website.

###  **Use of Cookies**

"Cookies" are small files that enable us to store information related to your device and you, the user, specifically, while you visit one of our websites. Cookies help us to determine how frequently our internet pages are accessed as well as the number of users. They also help us configure our offers so that they are as convenient and efficient as possible for you.

On the basis of Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR, we are using "session cookies" in order to optimise our website and to guarantee an undisturbed user experience. These cookies are stored exclusively for the duration of your visit to our internet pages. They are automatically deleted when you close your browser.

In addition, we use "persistent cookies" for retaining information about visitors who repeatedly access one of our internet pages. The purpose of using cookies is to be able to offer you optimal user guidance as well as to "recognise" you and thus be able to present (as much as possible) diversified internet pages and new contents during repeated use. Our website contains a cookie banner, which provides you the opportunity to either agree or disagree to the collection of cookies. This based on consent provided by you. The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies for analysis purposes is Art. 6 (1) a GDPR. You have the right to object and to opt out (see: How to Manage cookies).

**Generally, we do not create an individual profile of your online activities. The content of a persistent cookie is limited to an identification number. Name, email address, IP address, etc., are not saved on the majority of our sites. However, there are some exceptions which you can find in our cookie table below.**

There are two exceptions:

**1) MediaMind Tracking Cookies.** These persistent tracking cookies collect your IP address and uses it to provide geographical location data to help DHL monitor and manage advertising campaigns. The cookies are completely encrypted and do not collect any other personally identifiable data, so the IP address cannot be linked to personal data and is not shared with third parties. The IP address is stored securely and only used confidentially by DHL internally to provide aggregated reports. The cookies expire after 30 days.

You can learn more about MediaMind Tracking cookies in the DHL Table of Cookies below.

Alternatively, to opt out of being tracked by MediaMind across all websites, you can do so by clicking on the MediaMind Opt-Out link: [MediaMind Opt-Out](http://ds.serving-sys.com/OBA/MediaMind/OptOut.aspx)

If you've previously opted out, and would like to reverse your setting, click the MediaMind Opt-In link: [MediaMind Opt-In](http://ds.serving-sys.com/OBA/MediaMind/OptIn.aspx)

**2) Google Analytics Cookies.** A small number of countries may use Google Analytics cookies on a small scale for specific local purposes. These cookies use your IP address as recognition, however do not identify you as an individual. In other words, information is collected in an anonymous form. The cookies collect information about how visitors use our local sites and use the information to compile reports and to help us improve local sites.

You can learn more about Google Analytics in the DHL Table of Cookies below.

**DHL Table of Cookies and Categories**

We have provided details of all cookies used on this websites in the table below.

All cookies in this table have been categorized according to 4 numbered groups – the relevant category numbers are listed in column 1. Please note that cookies can belong to more than one category.

The categories are as follows:

[1] Strictly Necessary: These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided. As already stated above, this is based on Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR.

[2] Performance: These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works.

[3] Functionality: These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. For example, these cookies can be used to remember and store the last tracking number that you entered when using a tracking application. Information these cookies collect may be anonymized and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

[4] Targeting or Advertising: These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as helping measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator’s permission.

**Cookie** |  **Name** |  **Purpose** |  **More Information**  
---|---|---|---  
Allow cookies for site |  dhlpcp |  If set to 1 the user has allowed the site to write cookies. If this cookie doesn’t exist, no cookies are allowed. |     
  |  dhlah | 

Closed article (was viewed). Expires after 365 days.

|     
  |  dhlolc | 

Closed overlay (was viewed). Expires after 30 days.

|     
Recaptcha-Cookie |  nocap |  This cookie is created e.g. when you send us a message via contact form and have successfully solved the Recaptcha. |     
Campaign name Cookie [2] |  campaignName | 

This cookie is created when you arrive at a DHL web page from a DHL promotional banner or from a link contained in a campaign / promotional email.

The cookie stores a campaign ID, which uniquely identifies the campaign source.

If you contact DHL using one of our online contact or registration forms within 24 hours of arriving at one of our websites, the campaign ID is attached with the email sent to DHL Sales or Customer Service.

This information is solely used to assess how successful our campaigns are and monitor if customers have contacted us as a result of a campaign.

The cookie stores no personal customer data at all, only the campaign's ID.

The cookie expires after 24 hours only.

|     
Webtrends Analytics [2] |  WT_FPC | 

This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

The cookie is only used for identification and does not hold visitor personal data, only an identifier. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience.

|  More Info about Privacy at [Webtrends](http://webtrends.com/privacy-policy/)  
Webtrends Analytics [2] |  ACOOKIE | 

This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our sites and is specifically used to monitor visitors across DHL domains.

For example, if a visitor arrives at our corporate site (domain is www.dhl.com) and then selects to visit a DHL country website with its own local domain (e.g. for Germany, local domain is www.dhl.de).

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

The cookie is only used for identification and does not hold visitor personal data, only an identifier. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience.

|  More Info about Privacy at [Webtrends](http://webtrends.com/privacy-policy/)  
Google Analytics [2] | 

_utma

_utmb

_utmz

| 

Certain countries also use Google Analytics for specific local purposes.

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our local sites. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve local sites. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the local site, where visitors have come to the local site from and the pages they visited

|  More Info about Privacy at [Google](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)  
Google Analytics [2] |  _ga | 

This cookie is used to distinguish users. The cookie expires after 2 years.

| 

More information about this cookie at [Google](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)  
  
Google Analytics [2] |  _gid |  This cookie is used to distinguish users. The cookie expires after 24 hours only. | 

More information about this cookie at [Google](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)  
  
Google Analytics [2] |  _gat |  This cookie is used to throttle request rate. The cookie expires after 1 minute only. | 

More information about this cookie at [Google](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)  
  
MediaMind Cookies [2] |  U2, ActivityInfo, TargetingInfo, Eyeblaster, A3, B4, and C4. | 

MediaMind cookies are created when you arrive at specific DHL campaign web pages from a DHL promotional banner, from a link contained in a campaign / promotional email, or when you have used a campaign link provided as part of an offline media advertisement.

MediaMind cookies track when and where you were exposed to DHL ads online, how you engaged with those ads, and when you visited the DHL site after being exposed to those ads.

The information is used to help DHL measure the performance of advertising campaigns. The information is provided as aggregated reports, so no individual user information will be viewed. It does not monitor any other browsing behaviour and is used confidentially only by DHL internally.

|  More Info about Privacy at [MediaMind](http://www.sizmek.com/about-us/privacy)  
Flash Cookies [1] |  LSO | 

Flash Cookies allow you to view Flash Player content and are independent of DHL.

Flash Player default settings do not seek user's permission to store cookies on local hard disk.

If you wish, you can disable flash cookies (also referred to as 'local shared objects').

| 

More info about how to manage or disable [Flash cookies](http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html#main_where%20%E2%80%93%20instructions)

Full info on Flash Player functionality and related Privacy settings [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/help01.html)  
  
YouTube Cookies [2] | 

use_hitbox

VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE

| 

We embed videos using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. Some of these videos are from our official YouTube channel.

This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.

|  To find out more, please visit YouTube's embedding videos information [page](http://support.google.com/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780)  
Adobe Analytics [2] |  s_cc |  This cookie has been set by the JavaScript code and read to determine whether cookies have been enabled. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed. | 

More information about privacy at [Adobe](https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_analytics.html)  
  
Adobe Analytics [2] |  s_sq |  This cookie collects information anonymously about what link the user has clicked. Its aim is to discover which links are used and which are not, in order to improve web offers. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed. | 

More information about privacy at [Adobe](https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_analytics.html)  
  
Adobe Analytics [2] |  s_vi |  This cookie is used to detect a return visitor as one and the same user and collect information on how our website is used. We use this information to develop the website further and provide users with content that is more appropriate to them. The cookie collects the above information anonymously (individual visitor ID, time / date stamp). This is a permanent cookie and expires after 5 years. | 

More information about privacy at [Adobe](https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_analytics.html)  
  
Adobe Analytics [2] |  s_fid | 

This cookie is used to identify a unique visitor if the standard s_vi cookie is unavailable due to third-party cookie restrictions. Not used for implementations that use first-party cookies.

This is a permanent cookie and expires after 5 years.

| 

More information about privacy at [Adobe](https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_analytics.html)  
  
  |  __cfduid |  Persistent cookie of Cloudflare. |  More Info at [Cloudflare](https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do-)  
  |  X-AUTH-TOKEN |  Cookie authentication and login. Contains user info; (user_id, roles and email), This is a session cookie so after closing a session, info is deleted. |     
  |  XSRF-TOKEN |  Session cookie. For secure communication between browser and server. |     
  
If you use the **DHL Finder (location search)** , we also set the following cookies:

**Cookie** |  **Name** |  **Purpose** |  **More Information**  
---|---|---|---  
i18next |    |  This cookie is used to recognize the language setting of the visitor, with a view to making the website experience more pleasant. This information is used to determine which language is suitable for the visitor and the language setting is set accordingly. The cookie collects the above information anonymously. It will only be used confidentially within DHL to improve the websites and the user experience. This cookie is a session cookie and expires when the browser is closed. |     
br<primaryKey> |    |  This cookie is used to recognize a returning visitor as one and the same user. This information is used to determine whether the visitor has already given a rating for a location. The cookie collects the above information anonymously (individual visitor ID, time/date stamp). The cookie expires after only 24 hours. |     
  
**Third Party Cookies in embedded content**

Please note that on some pages of our websites you may notice that cookies have been set that are not related to DHL. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Vimeo, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browser. DHL does not control the use of these cookies and cannot access them due to the way that cookies work, as cookies can only be accessed by the party who originally set them. You should check the third party websites for more information about these cookies.

**Web Beacons**

In order to keep DHL’s online content relevant easy to use and up-to-date, we use web analytics services such as Webtrends (See Webtrends entry in DHL Table of Cookies above for more information). These services use data collection technologies such as web beacons. Web beacons are small electronic images that deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage and website effectiveness. In turn, this lets us know what content is of interest to our visitors and helps us provide tailored information on our websites. These web beacons are anonymous and do not contain or collect any information that identifies you. The information is anonymous and only used for statistical purposes. These web analytics data and cookies cannot be used to identify you as a natural person as they never contain personal information such as your name or email address.

**How to Manage Cookies**

Using our products and services without cookies is also possible. In your browser, you can deactivate the saving of cookies, limit them to particular websites, or set the browser to notify you when a cookie is sent. You can also delete cookies from your PC hard drive at any time (file: "cookies"). Please note that in this case you will have to expect a limited page presentation and limited user guidance.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings.

  * To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit: [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)
  * For further EU-specific advice on cookies and the various opt out options available to you, you can also visit the following website: [Your Online Choices](http://youronlinechoices.eu/)
  * To opt out of being tracked by LiveBall, you will need to manage and delete the cookies using your browser settings.
  * To find out more, please visit: [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)
  * You can also choose to opt out of some or all of the advertising cookies set on your PC by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp#)
  * Not everyone who visits our site will do so using a web browser. For example, some users will access DHL websites or applications using a mobile device. If so, it may not be possible to disable cookies or adjust web browser settings.
  * To opt out of being tracked by dotMailer, you will need to manage and delete the cookies using your browser settings.
  * To find out more, please visit: [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)
  * To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit: [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)
  * To opt out of being tracked by MediaMind across all websites, you can do so by clicking on the MediaMind Opt-Out link: [MediaMind Opt-Out](http://ds.serving-sys.com/OBA/MediaMind/OptOut.aspx)
  * If you've previously opted out, and would like to reverse your setting, click the MediaMind Opt-In link: [MediaMind Opt-In](http://ds.serving-sys.com/OBA/MediaMind/OptIn.aspx)
  * To opt out of being tracked by WebTrends Analytics across all websites, visit: [Webtrends Opting Out of Tracking Cookies](https://ondemand.webtrends.com/support/optout.asp?action=out)
  * You are currently opted-in for web monitoring by Eloqua on DHL websites.
  * [Click here](https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/opt-status.html) to opt-out of Eloqua web monitoring.
  * To opt out of being tracked by Omniture across all websites, you can do so by clicking on the Omniture Opt-Out link: [Omniture Opt-Out](http://deutschepostag.112.2o7.net/optout.html?second=1&second_has_cookie=0&locale=de_DE)
  * If you've previously opted out, and would like to reverse your setting, click the Omniture Opt-In link: [Omniture Opt-In](http://www.112.2o7.net/optout.html?omniture=1&popup=1&locale=en_US&optin=1&second=1&second_has_cookie=0)

Please remember that if you delete your cookies, or use a different browser or computer you will need to set your opt-out status again.

###  **Contact forms**

There are contact forms on our website that can be used to contact us via electronic means. If the user takes advantage of this option, the data entered in the form will be transmitted to us and stored.

We use the personal data you provide solely for the technical administration of the websites and to fulfill your wishes and requirements – i.e. primarily to process contracts concluded with you or your enquiries.

[Here](http://www.dhlparcel.es/en/private-customers/contact.html) you will find examples of the type of data that is processed within the scope of the contact forms.

The processing of the personal data from the form primarily enables us to handle the contact processing. In addition, data may be processed in the course of processing a customer request.

The data will be processed primarily for the performance of the contract in accordance with Article 6 (1) b) GDPR and to safeguard legitimate interests in accordance with Article 6 (1) f) GDPR.

###  **How about data security?**

DHL takes all of the necessary technical and organisational security measures to protect your personal data from being lost or misused. For instance, your data is saved in a secure operating environment which is not accessible to the public. In certain cases, your personal data is encrypted by Secure Socket Layer technology (SSL) during transmission. This means that an approved encryption procedure is used for communication between your computer and the DHL servers if your browser supports SSL.

###  **Changes to Privacy Notice**

We keep our data protection statement under regular review.

DHL reserves the right to change its data protection statement at any time with or without prior notice. Please check back frequently to be informed of any changes. By using DHL's websites you agree to this Privacy Policy.

##  **Products and Services**

###  **Shipment Tracking**

Additional data protection information relating to shipment tracking:

**Type of data** |  **Example** |  **External access to data**  
---|---|---  
Item number |    |  Sender and recipient  
Name of sender |    |  Sender and recipient  
Address of sender |    |  Sender and recipient (after entering the postcode)  
Name of recipient |    |  Sender and recipient (after entering the postcode or as a logged-in and identified recipient)  
Address of recipient |    |  Sender  
Name of substitute recipient, if applicable |  Neighbor |  Sender and recipient (after entering the postcode or as a logged-in and identified recipient)  
Address of substitute recipient, if applicable |  Neighbor |  Sender  
Customer data of sender (EKP number, billing number) |    |  Sender  
Product name / service name (currently only in shipment tracking for business customers NOLB) |  DHL Paket, DHL Paket International, COD, Bulky Goods |  Sender and recipient (only for services relevant to the recipient, such as Bulky Goods and COD)  
Shipment progress |    |  Sender and recipient  
Signature of recipient (POD) |    |  Sender  
Confirmation of minimum age verification +16 / +18 |  Visual age check |  Sender  
  
**1\. Purposes of data processing - essential information**

We process your data in order, for instance, to

  * perform the parcel shipping contract concluded with you or a shipper;
  * display the status of a shipment or provide information via our customer service department;
  * fulfill obligations as part of statutory requirements;
  * fulfill our security requirements (e.g. for crime detection purposes);
  * compile statistics on the provision of our services; and
  * for purposes of quality assurance, process optimization and planning certainty.

**2\. Storage period**

The data will be stored for as long as they are required. The necessity ensues either from statutory retention periods.
